A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Unprocessed photographs, Series 7 FA460
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Unprocessed photographs, Series 7
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979
FA460
3.6 Cubic Feet 3 record storage cartons.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Photographic negatives cannot be handled or viewed by researchers due to the fragile nature of the format. To request duplication of an image(s), please contact an Archivist.
Related Archival Materials note
Additional images of Nelson A. Rockefeller and or his interests will be found in the following:
Rockefeller Family Photographs. Most of the photos of Nelson A. Rockefeller in his childhood and many photos of Nelson A. Rockefeller as an adult with his parents can be found in 1005 John D. Rockefeller Jr. Family - Children's Albums or Group Portraits. See also John D. Rockefeller Jr. - Business - 17 West 54th Street.
International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC) Archives.
Nelson A. Rockefeller papers, Art, Series C (FA340). This series documents the management of Nelson A. Rockefeller's art collection and includes photos of a portion of the works of art he owned.
Arrangement note
The Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs are arranged in the following series:
Series 1008: Nelson A. Rockefeller family. Series 2: Room 5600, Rockefeller family office. Series 3: Gubernatorial Press Office. Series 4: Gubernatorial Press Office. Series 5: Gubernatorial, Robart A. (Bob) Wands. Series 6: Vice Presidential. Series 7: Unprocessed photographs.
Conditions Governing Access note
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Arrangement note
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series:
Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
Other Finding Aids note
For other Rockefeller family photographic holdings, please see the following finding aids:
FA445 Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001
FA446 William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002
FA447 John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003
FA448 William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004
FA449 John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005
FA450 Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006
FA451 John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007
FA452 Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009
FA453 David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010
For related materials, please see the following finding aids:
FA340 Nelson A. Rockefeller papers, Art, Series C
FA084 International Basic Economy Corporation records
Other Finding Aids
For other Nelson A. Rockefeller photographic holdings, please see the following finding aids:
FA454 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Nelson A. Rockefeller family, Series 1008
FA455 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Room 5600, Rockefeller family office, Series 2
FA456 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Gubernatorial Press Office, Series 3
FA457 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Gubernatorial Press Office, Series 4
FA458 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Gubernatorial, Robert A. (Bob) Wands, Series 5
FA459 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Vice Presidential, Series 6
Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; New York (N.Y.); Arts; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Art, Modern; Political campaigns -- United States; New York (State); State governments -- United States; Rockefeller family -- Art collections; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979
- Unprocessed material, 7
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller - Political Albums I
    - Steuben County Visit, 1995 August (Box 1)
    - National Governors Conference, 1967 (Box 1)
    - National Governors Conference, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Campaign, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Allied Chemical Tower Dedication, 1995 December 2 (Box 1)
    - Victory Dinner, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Sterling Winthrop Research Institute, 1961 April 6 (Box 1)
    - NY State Building Ground Breaking, 1967 June 7 (Box 1)
    - Westchester County Republican Committee Dinner, 1954 January 21 (Box 1)
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller - Albums II
    - Campaign, 1964 (Box 2)
    - National Governors Conference, 1963 February 24 (Box 2)
    - Trip to Iran (Box 2)
    - Trip to South Africa, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Governors Conference, 1965 July 29 (Box 2)
    - Whitney Stakes, Saratoga Springs, 1962 August 4 (Box 2)
    - Dedication Day M&T Plaza (Box 2)
  - Photographs Not in Albums
    Appraisal
    Folders from Kendall Lutkins, 1986 June 13.
    - Campaign, 1958 (Box 3)
    - Campaign, 1960 (Box 3)
    - Campaign, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Worlds Fair, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Campaign, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Campaign, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Campaign, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Thomas Dewey (Box 3)
    - Revenue Sharing, 1970s (Box 3)
    - Executive Mansion (Box 3)
    - Expositions (Box 3)
    - NY State Power Authority (Box 3)
    - Raising Israeli Flag at Rockefeller Center, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Richard Nixon (Box 3)
    - Astronauts (Box 3)
    - Awards (Box 3)
    - Bob Hope (Box 3)
    - United Nations, San Francisco, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Lady Bird Johnson (Box 3)
    - Kykuit Dedication, 1976 (Box 3)